Whoa, that was a tough concept, but you handled it really well.
لقد كان مفهومًا صعبًا، لكنك تعاملت معه على نحوٍ جيد حقًا.
This unlocks the ability to build some really awesome layouts in Android
وهذا يوفر القدرة على بناء بعض المخططات الرائعة حقًا في آندرويد
because almost all screens contain some type of nested layouts,
لأن جميع لقطات الشاشة تقريبًا تحتوي على بعض أنواع المخططات المتداخلة،
which Correll was actually mentioning earlier in the Google Play app.
التي ذكرتها كوريل في وقت سابق في تطبيق جوجل بلاي.
After all of that prep work, now we're ready to go back into
بعد كل هذا العمل التحضيري، نحن الآن على استعداد للعودة إلى
Android Studio land to implement the changes for an improved quantity picker.
منصة آندرويد ستوديو لتطبيق التغييرات للحصول على ملتقط كمية متطور.
In case you're wondering, Katherine, what if I'm trying to build a layout and
عند سؤال كاثرين، ماذا لو كنت أحاول بناء مخطط
I don't have three options of XML layouts
وليس لدي الخيارات الثلاثة لمخططات إكس إم إل
magically appear before me that I have to choose from.
التي تظهر أمامي وعلي الاختيار من بينها.
Well, that's a fair question.
حسنًا، هذا سؤال منطقي.
So far we've practiced being able to read XML and
لقد مارسنا القدرة على قراءة إكس إم إل
draw a view hierarchy diagram.
ورسمنا الرسم البياني للتسلسل الهرمي لواجهة.
We've also practiced reading XML layouts and
كما مارسنا أيضًا قراءة مخططات إكس إم إل
drawing a sketch of what the screen would look like.
ورسمنا ما كان يظهر على الشاشة.
But now it's time to practice seeing a design of what we want to build and
ولكن الوقت حان لممارسة رؤية تصميم ما نريد بناؤه
being able to write the XML from it.
وأن نكون قادرين على كتابة إكس إم إل منها.
I do realize that I gave you the solution XML in the previous quiz.
أتفهم أني أعطيتك الحل "إكس إم إل" في الاختبار السابق.
I was somewhat paying attention, but I don't want you to look at that solution.
كنت مهتم بعض الشيء، ولكن لا أريد منك أن تنظر إلى هذا الحل.
I want you to practice the skill of seeing a screenshot or
أريدك أن تمارس مهارة رؤية لقطة الشاشة
a mock of what you want to build and then being able to write the XML for it.
أو صورة لما تريد بناؤه ومن ثم تكون قادرًا على كتابة إكس إم إل لها.
Normally, we would start with the desired screenshot
عادة ما نبدأ مع لقطة الشاشة المطلوبة
of what we want to build.
لما نريد بناؤه.
You can get this from a designer that's working on your team who's
يمكنك الحصول على هذا من المصمم الذي يعمل في فريق
designing the app for you.
تصميم التطبيق.
Or if you're working without a designer,
وإذا كنت تعمل دون وجود مصمم،
you could also sketch this out on your own.
يمكنك التعرف على ذلك بنفسك.
Then you would imagine how to break this down into views and ViewGroups.
وبعد ذلك، عليك أن تتخيل كيفية تلف هذا في الواجهات ومجموعات الواجهات.
You can mark it up and then try to draw out the view hierarchy diagram for
يمكنك وضع علامة عليها ثم حاول رسم الرسم البياني للتسلسل الهرمي للواجهة
the relationship between the children and the parent views.
من أجل العلاقة بين الواجهات الفرع والأصل.
After you finish this diagram, you can start writing out the skeleton for
بعد الانتهاء من هذا الرسم البياني، يمكنك بدء كتابة الهيكل الأساسي
what the XML layout code would look like.
لما سيبدو عليه كود مخطط إكس إم إل.
I'll leave these parts as an exercise for you.
سأترك هذه الأجزاء كتمرين لك.
You'll make your changes in the activity_main.xml layout file.
ستقوم بإجراء التغييرات في ملف المخطط activity_main.xml.
Aside from writing your XML here and
إضافة إلى كتابة إكس إم إل هنا
seeing a preview of it, you can also click on the design pane here.
ورؤية معاينة لها، يمكنك أيضًا النقر فوق لوحة التصميم.
This is Design tab as opposed to the Text tab.
هذه علامة تبويب التصميم بدلا من علامة تبويب النص.
The Design pane allows you to drag and drop views onto the device.
تسمح لك لوحة التصميم بسحب وإسقاط الواجهات في الجهاز.
You can also see the component tree in the top right corner here.
كما يمكنك رؤية شجرة المكونات أعلى الزاوية اليمنى هنا.
This is, essentially, a tree of all the views in your hierarchy.
في الأساس، هذه شجرة لجميع الواجهات في التسلسل الهرمي.
Currently we have vertical LinearLayout, that's the parent view, and
والآن لدينا مخطط خطي عمودي، ويمثل الواجهة الأصل،
all these children views inside of it.
وجميع الواجهات الفرع داخله.
If you had nested ViewGroups, they would also show up here.
إذا كان لديك مجموعات واجهات متداخلة، فقد تظهر هنا أيضًا.
Now go ahead and build this layout in Android Studio.
وان استمر وقم ببناء هذا المخطط في آندرويد ستوديو.
After you've selected and positioned the views, remember to style them so
بعد قيامك باختيار الواجهات وتحديد مكانها، لا تنسى تنسيقها
it looks like this.
كي تبدو هكذا.
The style of the views is mostly the same,
غالبا ما يبدو تنسيق الواجهات متشابها،
except note that there's eight dp of space in-between the minus button and
باستثناء ملاحظة أن هناك 8 بكسل كثافة لمسافة بين الزر -
the two and in-between the two and the plus button.
والقيمة 2 وبين القيمة 2 والزر +.
As mentioned earlier, avoid looking at the code and
كما ذكر سابقًا، تجنب النظر في الكود
try implementing it yourself.
وحاول تطبيق ذلك بنفسك.
When you're done, check this box to continue.
عند الانتهاء، حدد هذا المربع للمتابعة.